So, we start with this. If you look it
up all over, why do startups fail,
you'll find this 20 top reasons why they
fail. But, the first and foremost, and
usually this is what happens in any
industry, is the inability to understand
market and customer demand. So,
basically, creating something that is
for nothing and for no one, because no
one will then buy it.
Why does this happen? It happens because
usually we create tech and stuff based
on what we think it is needed.
This is what we think and what actually
happens in the real world, uh can be two
very different things. And before we
talk to the market, we talk to
customers, and we actually validate our
ideas in a way in which it works, we
don't just give them money to tell us
that our idea is good just so that we
feel fulfilled,
then this is why startups fail.
Basically, they move on with a product,
maybe they also raise some money or put
their own money in it, and at the end no
one actually pays for it, and they need
to lose everything that they've invested
just because they didn't validate from
the very beginning that the thing they
are building will actually sell.
And why do I say that it is important to
sell? Now, um
you are here in Innovation Labs because
of course everyone will ask you about
your business model, about how you're
selling. You'll also learn about
business models here, you can also learn
from everywhere, but um what it is
important for a business, because this
is why it's called a business. It's not
a hobby, it's not a sidekick, it's not
an NGO, it's not a social project. It's
a business. You need to sell, you need
to make money, because otherwise, it's
it is a hobby. That is the point of
startups, either make a lot of money and
be
uh profitable or exit and sell and be
very very profitable for the founders or
people that have a stake in the company.
And also, in the area of investors,
everyone wants to get money out of it,
of course. The second, of course, is
spending money and running out of cash.
You might think that
um I don't know, 100,000
uh euros is a lot of money or 1 million
is a lot of money. But when you're in a
startup,
that becomes a runaway. So, you need to
make sure that you have money in that
runaway so that you can support your
company with all of the growth that is
coming. Because when someone invests in
a company, they expect for you to grow.
So, you need to invest the money super
smartly. And usually,
startups fail because they run out of
money. And guess what? Even though maybe
they have clients in their pipeline,
they will need to close because they
cannot pay for their servers or
something like that.
Third is the inability to form and
maintain a diverse team.
Maybe this is something that changed a
bit now due to AI because the diverse
team
um
is everyone. So, everyone should be
diverse at the moment. So, you shouldn't
have just wear one hat because now you
can learn everything from the beginning
and do everything.
But
uh the inability to form uh a team uh is
something that everyone actually, not
only in startups, but in everything that
you do, also in NGOs. So, let's say
innovation labs has a team behind. It is
difficult to do leading and leadership
in the team. So, you might also think
about that.